livemetallica.com 2019-06-07

# The entire Metallica show catalog - Privacy Policy

**WELCOME TO THE LIVEMETALLICA.COM PRIVACY POLICY**

-updated as of May 25, 2018

Thank you for visiting livemetallica.com. Your privacy is important to us. This privacy policy describes the information we collect, what we do with it, and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used at livemetallica.com.  Please review our privacy policy as it may change from time to time in the future (when we change the policy in a material way, a notice will be posted on our website along with the updated Privacy Policy) and contact us at [help@livemetallica.com](mailto:help@livemetallica.com) if you have any questions or concerns.

**The Information We Collect**

At livemetallica.com, you can order products, express an opinion, and subscribe to services such as online newsletters and paid streaming. The types of personally identifiable information that may be collected at these pages include: name, address, location, e-mail address, telephone number, fax number, contact preferences, credit card information, Internet protocol address, date of birth, and details of how you use and interact with our websites (e.g. your search queries, a record of customer service emails, access dates and times, referring website addresses).

At some parts of some of our websites, only persons who provide us with the requested personally identifiable information will be able to order products, programs, and services or otherwise participate in the site's activities and offerings.

We also may collect some non-personally identifiable information when you visit many of our web pages such as the type of browser you are using (e.g. Safari, Internet Explorer), the type of operating system you are using and information about your Internet service provider (e.g. Comcast, AT&T) or device (e.g. iPhone 6, MacBook Pro) and other user-related general data (e.g. zip code, area code).

**How We Use the Information**

We may use the information you provide about yourself to fulfill your requests for our products, programs, and services, to respond to your inquiries about our offerings, and to offer you other products, programs or services that we believe may be of interest to you.  We sometimes use this information to communicate with you, such as to notify you when a concert you have purchased is available for download or when we make changes to our subscriber agreements, to fulfill a request by you for an online newsletter, or to contact you about your account with us.  If you enter into a giveaway, contest or other promotion, we may use the information you provide to administer those programs.

The information we collect in connection with our website is used to provide an interactive experience. We use this information to facilitate participation in these online forums and communities and, from time to time, to offer you new products, programs, or services.  As is the case with most Internet services, we obtain some information automatically and store it in log files.  We use this and other information to understand and analyze trends, to administer the site, to learn about user behavior on the site, to improve our products and services, and to gather demographic information about our users.  We may use this information to market and advertise our products and services.

You are not required to provide any personally-identifiable information that we have requested, but if you choose not to do so, in many cases we will not be able to provide you with our products or services or respond to any questions you may have.

We sometimes use the non-personally identifiable information that we collect to improve the design and content of our site and to enable us to personalize your Internet experience. We also may share non-personally identifiable information publicly and with our partners and use this information in the aggregate to analyze site usage, as well as to offer you products, programs, or services.

We may disclose personally identifiable information in response to legal process (e.g. in response to a court order or a subpoena) or to enforce applicable Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations.  We also may disclose such information to detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, intellectual property violations, security or technical issues, to protect our operations or users, or to respond to a law enforcement agency's request.  Additionally, in the event of a reorganization, merger or sale we may transfer any and all information we collect to the relevant third party.

Agents and contractors of livemetallica.com who have access to personally identifiable information are required to protect this information in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Notice by, for example, not using the information for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for livemetallica.com.  Agents and contractors of livemetallica.com will comply with all laws regulating these matters, including the General Data Protection Regulation (EU).

Although we take appropriate measures to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of information, we cannot assure you that personally identifiable information that we collect will never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Notice.

Finally, livemetallica.com websites will not use or transfer personally identifiable information provided to us in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you with an opportunity to opt out of these unrelated uses.  For example, if you don’t want to be on our mailing list, you can opt out by updating your settings or contacting us at [help@livemetallica.com](mailto:help@livemetallica.com).

**Cookies**

To enhance your experience with our website, many of our web pages use "cookies."  Cookies are text files we place in your computer's browser to store your preferences. Cookies, by themselves, do not tell us your e-mail address or other personally identifiable information unless you choose to provide this information to us by, for example, registering at our site. However, once you choose to furnish the site with personally identifiable information, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie.

We use cookies to understand site usage and to improve the content and offerings on our site. For example, we may use cookies to personalize your experience at livemetallica.com.com (e.g. to recognize you by name when you return to our site), save your password in password-protected areas, and enable you to use shopping carts on our website.

You may also set your browser to block all cookies, including cookies associates with our services, or to indicate when a cookie is being set by us.  However, many of our services may not function properly if your cookies are disabled.

**Our Commitment to Security**

We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and help prevent unauthorized access, maintain data security, and correctly use the information we collect online.  livemetallica.com may work with third-parties in order to ensure proper authentication and security procedures and practices.

**General Data Protection Regulation (EU)**

With regard to your right of access, if you ask us, we’ll confirm whether we’re processing your personal information and, if so, provide you with a copy of that personal information (along with certain other details).  If you require additional copies, we may need to charge a reasonable fee.

With regard to your right of rectification, if the personal information we hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete, you are entitled to have it rectified.  If we’ve shared your personal information with others, we’ll let them know about the rectification where possible.  If you ask us, where possible and lawful to do so, we’ll also tell you who we’ve shared your personal information with so that you can contact them directly.

With regard to your right of erasure, you can ask us to delete or remove your personal information in some circumstances such as where we no longer need it, or you withdraw your consent (where applicable).  If we’ve shared your personal information with others, we’ll let them know about the erasure where possible.  If you ask us, where possible and lawful to do so, we’ll also tell you who we’ve shared your personal information with so that you can contact them directly.

With regard to your right to restrict processing, you can ask us to ‘block’ or suppress the processing of your personal information in certain circumstances such as where you contest the accuracy of that personal information or object to us processing it.  It won’t stop us from storing your personal information though.  We will tell you before we lift any restriction.  If we’ve shared your personal information with others, we’ll let them know about the restriction where possible.  If you ask us, where possible and lawful to do so, we’ll also tell you who we’ve shared your personal information with so that you can contact them directly.

With regard to your right to data portability, you have the right as of May 25th 2018, in certain circumstances, to obtain personal information you’ve provided us with (in a structured, commonly-used format) and to reuse it elsewhere.

With regard to your right to object, you can ask us to stop processing your personal information, and we will do so, if we are: relying on our own or someone else’s legitimate interests to process your personal information except if we can demonstrate compelling legal grounds for the processing; processing your personal information for direct marketing; or processing your personal information for research unless such processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest.

With regard to your rights in relation to automated decision-making and profiling, you have the right not to be subject to a decision when it’s based on automatic processing, including profiling, and it produces a legal effect or similarly significantly affects you unless such profiling is necessary for entering into, or the performance of, a contract between you and livemetallica.com.

With regard to your right to withdraw content, if we rely on your consent (or explicit consent) as our legal basis for processing your personal information, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time.

We will perform Data Protection Impact Assessments to identify risks to consumer data and Data Protection Compliance Reviews to ensure those risks are addressed.

In the event of a security breach involving your personal user data, we will notify you within 72 hours of learning of the breach and will provide specific details of the breach such as the nature of it and the approximate number of data subjects affected.

**California Privacy Disclosures:**

We do not track our customers across third party websites, however some third party sites do keep track of your browsing activities when they provide you content, which allows them to determine what they present to you.  If you are visiting such sites, your browser should allow you to set the Do Not Track (DNT) signal so that third parties know you do not want to be tracked.  Third parties that have content embedded on livemetallica.com websites may set cookies on a user’s browser and/or collect information about the fact that a web browser visited a specific livemetallica.com website from a certain IP address.  Third parties cannot obtain any other personally identifiable information from livemetallica.com’s websites unless you provide it to them directly.  Information collected by third parties is governed by their privacy practices.

livemetallica.com offers interactive services which allow you to post content to share publicly or with friends.  At any time you can contact [help@livemetallica.com](mailto:help@livemetallica.com) to delete or remove content you have posted using the deletion or removal options within our service.  Although we offer deletion capability for our services, please be aware that the removal of content may not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of that content or information posted through the services.

**How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions or concerns about the livemetallica.com Privacy Policy for this site, its implementation, or to exercise your legal rights you may contact us at [help@livemetallica.com](mailto:help@livemetallica.com) or at the address below:

LiveMetallica, 1383 Ninth Avenue, San Francisco, CA 94122 attn: Privacy

BACK TO TOP
